Pitt/Hollis mss., 1773-1894 LMC 2969
Lilly Library
Pitt/Hollis mss.
1773-1894
Lilly Library
LMC 2969
1 Volume
The Pitt/Hollis mss., 1773-1894, consist of correspondence between William Pitt the Elder and Thomas Hollis, as well as letters from Lady Hester Pitt to Hollis.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase: 2022
Biographical Note
William Pitt the Elder, 1st Earl of Chatham (1708-1778) was a British politician who served as Prime Minister of Great Britain from 1766-1768. Thomas Hollas V (1720-1774) was an English political philosopher and author. Pitt was one of his political heroes and inspirations.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of one bound volume with eleven autograph letters from Pitt to Hollis and twelve true copies of autograph letters from Hollis to Pitt tipped in. Also present are five letters from Lady Hester Pitt to Hollis.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged following original order.
- Contemporaneous autograph copy of a letter from Thomas Hollis to William Pitt the Elder, 3 January 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter signed from William Pitt the Elder to Thomas Hollis, 4 January 1773 (Bound 1)
- Contemporaneous autograph copy of a letter signed from Hollis to Pitt, 5 January 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter signed from Pitt to Hollis, 5 January 1773 (Bound 1)
- Contemporaneous autograph copy of a letter signed from Hollis to Pitt, 31 January 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter signed from Pitt to Hollis, 3 February 1773 (Bound 1)
- Contemporaneous autograph copy of a letter signed from Hollis to Pitt, 15 February 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Lady Hester Pitt to Hollis, 15 March 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Lady Hester Pitt to Hollis, 31 March 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter signed from Pitt to Hollis, 13 April 1773 (Bound 1)
- Contemporaneous autograph copy of a letter signed from Hollis to Pitt, 14 April 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter signed from Pitt to Hollis, 18 April 1773 (Bound 1)
- Contemporaneous autograph copy of a letter signed from Hollis to Pitt, 19 April 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Lord and Lady Pitt to Hollis, 9 May 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Hollis to Pitt, 9 May 1773 (Bound 1)
- Contemporaneous autograph copy of a letter from Hollis to Pitt, 21 June 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Pitt to Hollis, 22 June 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Pitt to Hollis, 20 July 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Hollis to Pitt, 21 July 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter and response between Pitt and Hollis, 29 July 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Pitt to Hollis, 12 September 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Hollis to Pitt, 13 September 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Pitt to Hollis, 18 September 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Lady Hester Pitt to Hollis, 30 November 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Lady Hester Pitt to Hollis, 11 December 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Hollis to Lady Hester Pitt, 13 December 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter from Lady Hester Pitt to Hollis, 15 December 1773 (Bound 1)
- Autograph letter signed from Thomas H. Baker to Alfred Morrison, 25 January 1894 (Bound 1)
- Two autograph poems in unknown hand dedicated to Pitt (Bound 1)